Courses

* * *

LoginSign Up

Login / Sign Up

Courses

Privacy Policy
==============

Last Updated on 8th September 2023, 12:23:00 PM IST

Data Usage Policy
-----------------

This document outlines how CodeChef collects, stores, and uses your data. It also provides you with information on how to remove your stored data on request, and what data will be removed. Please read this document carefully before proceeding with using the CodeChef website. By reading this page, you agree to abide by the terms of this policy. We reserve the right to update this policy as and when needed and will update you about the same on the email ID associated with your CodeChef account. Additionally, please also read our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and Community Guidelines before using the CodeChef website.

When you browse our website, we also automatically receive your computer's internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.

CodeChef collects data from you to identify you as a user, to be able to communicate with you, and to help ensure that all our users get the best experience while using our services. With your permission, we may use your registered email address to send you communication about our newsletters, your submission results and other updates.CodeChef does not share your data with any third parties without your explicit consent. We also store your data with adequate security features and remove personally identifiable information for analytics purposes.

CodeChef retains ownership over some of your data which includes the username which you reserved while registering, the analytical data collected from you such as your preferred language, your institution, your degree, your graduation year, the type of user you are, and how long you have been programming for. However, personally identifiable data associated with these, such as your real name, email ID, age, gender, and others will be removed on request. Note however that we retain the rights to publicly display the submissions that you had made, as detailed [here](https://www.codechef.com/terms).

Please see below for a detailed list of fields that will be removed on request:

'Full Name'  
'Gender'  
'Picture'  
'Date of Birth'  
'Address'  
'Pincode'  
'Phone'  
'Description'  
'Motto'  
'URL'  
'LinkedIn'  
'Resume'  
'Job Interest'  
'Email subscription for submission results'
'Email subscription for newsletters'  

Please follow the below steps to permanently delete your account:

1. Login to your CodeChef account.
2. Go to Edit Profile section.
3. Click on Privacy tab in the left bar.
4. Kindly take a look at the Privacy policy before proceeding.
5. Scroll to the bottom and click "I don't want to continue with CodeChef".

Thereafter, you can follow the instructions on the screen. Please remember that account deletion is not reversible and you will not be able to recover your data once your account has been deleted.

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us. However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers. In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

Once you leave our website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

When you click on links on our store, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

Cookie Notice
-------------

We use cookies to personalise your experience, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use our website.

We use [Clarity](https://clarity.microsoft.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Clarity is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Clarity uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Clarity stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Clarity nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Clarity’s privacy statement by clicking on [this link](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-US/privacystatement).

Currently, Clarity does not currently respond to browser DNT signals. Meaning, you can not opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Clarity’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Clarity’s use of tracking cookies on other websites

Other Policies
--------------

Learning Courses

Practice Paths

Online Compilers

Miscellaneous

Follow Us

We use cookies to improve your experience and for analytical purposes. Read our [Privacy Policy](https://www.codechef.com/privacy-policy) and [Terms](https://www.codechef.com/terms) to know more. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use our website.

Okay
